[
    {
        "question": "فَتَأْتُونَ",
        "answer": "and you will come forth",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "fatatūna",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُنْفَخُ فِي الصُّورِ فَتَأْتُونَ أَفْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اتَّخَذَ",
        "answer": "let him take",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "ittakhadha",
        "frequency": "273",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take",
        "waznTlit": "ittakhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَذِنَ",
        "answer": "permits",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 29,
        "tlit": "adhina",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ذ ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَذِنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to permit",
        "waznTlit": "adhina",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "449",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍa",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ مِهَادًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "450",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍi",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "551",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا فَلَنْ نَزِيدَكُمْ إِلَّا عَذَابًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "651",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا حَمِيمًا وَغَسَّاقًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "652",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "(About) which",
        "pcklId": "1399",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي هُمْ فِيهِ مُخْتَلِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "towards",
        "pcklId": "725",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَآبًا",
        "answer": "a place of return",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 83,
        "tlit": "maāban",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلطَّاغِينَ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "أ و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَـَٔاب",
        "waznEnglish": "Repeat praises",
        "waznTlit": "maāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَآبًا",
        "answer": "a return",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 83,
        "tlit": "maāban",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "أ و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَـَٔاب",
        "waznEnglish": "Repeat praises",
        "waznTlit": "maāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِآيَاتِنَا",
        "answer": "Our Signs",
        "pcklId": "378",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "biāyātinā",
        "frequency": "382",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَرْدًا",
        "answer": "coolness",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 113,
        "tlit": "bardan",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا بَرْدًا وَلَا شَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ر د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَرْد",
        "waznEnglish": "cool[ness]",
        "waznTlit": "bard",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَنَيْنَا",
        "answer": "And We constructed",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "wabanaynā",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنَيْنَا فَوْقَكُمْ سَبْعًا شِدَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to construct, to build",
        "waznTlit": "banā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْوَابًا",
        "answer": "gateways",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 166,
        "tlit": "abwāban",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُتِحَتِ السَّمَاءُ فَكَانَتْ أَبْوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ب و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the gate",
        "waznTlit": "bā wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "answer": "(is) between both of them",
        "pcklId": "301",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahumā",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَتْرَابًا",
        "answer": "well-matched",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "atrāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَوَاعِبَ أَتْرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "atrāb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُرَابًا",
        "answer": "dust",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 179,
        "tlit": "turāban",
        "frequency": "22",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "15",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُ الْكَافِرُ يَا لَيْتَنِي كُنْتُ تُرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تُرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "well-matched",
        "waznTlit": "turāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثَجَّاجًا",
        "answer": "pouring abundantly",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 198,
        "tlit": "thajjājan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ الْمُعْصِرَاتِ مَاءً ثَجَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ث ج ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ث ج ج",
        "waznEnglish": "pouring abundantly",
        "waznTlit": "thā jīm jīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْجِبَالَ",
        "answer": "And the mountains",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "wal-jibāla",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجِبَالَ أَوْتَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالُ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibālu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسُيِّرَتِ الْجِبَالُ فَكَانَتْ سَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَزَاءً",
        "answer": "A recompense",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "jazāan",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً وِفَاقًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "avail",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَزَاءً",
        "answer": "(As) a reward",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "jazāan",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً مِنْ رَبِّكَ عَطَاءً حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "avail",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْعَلِ",
        "answer": "We made",
        "pcklId": "331",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "najʿali",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ مِهَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "332",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا نَوْمَكُمْ سُبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "333",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا اللَّيْلَ لِبَاسًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "334",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا النَّهَارَ مَعَاشًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We placed",
        "pcklId": "335",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا سِرَاجًا وَهَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "And gardens",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "wajannātin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَنَّاتٍ أَلْفَافًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَبًّا",
        "answer": "grain",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 284,
        "tlit": "ḥabban",
        "frequency": "95",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لِنُخْرِجَ بِهِ حَبًّا وَنَبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "has endeared",
        "waznTlit": "ḥabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَدَائِقَ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 299,
        "tlit": "ḥadāiqa",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " حَدَائِقَ وَأَعْنَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ح د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح د ق",
        "waznEnglish": "gardens",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā dāl qāf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِسَابًا",
        "answer": "an account",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 316,
        "tlit": "ḥisāban",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا لَا يَرْجُونَ حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ح س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِسَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "(do) you think",
        "waznTlit": "ḥisāb",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حِسَابًا",
        "answer": "(according to) account",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 316,
        "tlit": "ḥisāban",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً مِنْ رَبِّكَ عَطَاءً حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ح س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِسَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "(do) you think",
        "waznTlit": "ḥisāb",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْصَيْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We have enumerated it",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 329,
        "tlit": "aḥṣaynāhu",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلَّ شَيْءٍ أَحْصَيْنَاهُ كِتَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ص ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْصَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to count, to calculate, to enumerate",
        "waznTlit": "aḥṣā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْقَابًا",
        "answer": "(for) ages",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 342,
        "tlit": "aḥqāban",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَابِثِينَ فِيهَا أَحْقَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْقَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "(for) ages",
        "waznTlit": "aḥqāb",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَقُّ",
        "answer": "the True",
        "pcklId": "276",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "l-ḥaqu",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمِيمًا",
        "answer": "scalding water",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "ḥamīman",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا حَمِيمًا وَغَسَّاقًا",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِنُخْرِجَ",
        "answer": "That We may bring forth",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "linukh'rija",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِنُخْرِجَ بِهِ حَبًّا وَنَبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bring forth, to drive out",
        "waznTlit": "akhraja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خِطَابًا",
        "answer": "(to) address",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 418,
        "tlit": "khiṭāban",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ لَا يَمْلِكُونَ مِنْهُ خِطَابًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ط ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خِطَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "address Me",
        "waznTlit": "khiṭāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُخْتَلِفُونَ",
        "answer": "(in) disagreement",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 430,
        "tlit": "mukh'talifūna",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي هُمْ فِيهِ مُخْتَلِفُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّخْتَلِف",
        "waznEnglish": "Take my place",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'talif",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَخَلَقْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "And We created you",
        "pcklId": "169",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "wakhalaqnākum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَخَلَقْنَاكُمْ أَزْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "دِهَاقًا",
        "answer": "full",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 490,
        "tlit": "dihāqan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَأْسًا دِهَاقًا",
        "rootWord": "د ه ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د ه ق",
        "waznEnglish": "full",
        "waznTlit": "dāl hā qāf",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَذُوقُونَ",
        "answer": "they will taste",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "yadhūqūna",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا بَرْدًا وَلَا شَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذُوقُوا",
        "answer": "So taste",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "fadhūqū",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا فَلَنْ نَزِيدَكُمْ إِلَّا عَذَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "927",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً مِنْ رَبِّكَ عَطَاءً حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "Lord",
        "pcklId": "928",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "929",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرْجُونَ",
        "answer": "expecting",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 540,
        "tlit": "yarjūna",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا لَا يَرْجُونَ حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْجُوا۟",
        "waznEnglish": "to hope, to expect, to desire",
        "waznTlit": "yarjū",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "answer": "the Most Gracious",
        "pcklId": "88",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥmāni",
        "frequency": "339",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحْمَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحْمَٰنُ",
        "answer": "the Most Gracious",
        "pcklId": "89",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥmānu",
        "frequency": "339",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحْمَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِرْصَادًا",
        "answer": "lying in wait",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 558,
        "tlit": "mir'ṣādan",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ جَهَنَّمَ كَانَتْ مِرْصَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ر ص د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِرْصَاد",
        "waznEnglish": "waiting",
        "waznTlit": "mir'ṣād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرُّوحُ",
        "answer": "the Spirit",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "l-rūḥu",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَقُومُ الرُّوحُ وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُوح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rūḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزْوَاجًا",
        "answer": "(in) pairs",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "azwājan",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَخَلَقْنَاكُمْ أَزْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَزِيدَكُمْ",
        "answer": "We will increase you",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 643,
        "tlit": "nazīdakum",
        "frequency": "61",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا فَلَنْ نَزِيدَكُمْ إِلَّا عَذَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ز ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to increase",
        "waznTlit": "zāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "answer": "are they asking one another",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yatasāalūna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَمَّ يَتَسَاءَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَسَآءَلُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to question, to ask, to inquire",
        "waznTlit": "yatasāalu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُبَاتًا",
        "answer": "(for) rest",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 650,
        "tlit": "subātan",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا نَوْمَكُمْ سُبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُبَات",
        "waznEnglish": "they had Sabbath",
        "waznTlit": "subāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبْعًا",
        "answer": "seven",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 653,
        "tlit": "sabʿan",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنَيْنَا فَوْقَكُمْ سَبْعًا شِدَادًا",
        "rootWord": "س ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبْع",
        "waznEnglish": "seven",
        "waznTlit": "sabʿ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَرَابًا",
        "answer": "a mirage",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 675,
        "tlit": "sarāban",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسُيِّرَتِ الْجِبَالُ فَكَانَتْ سَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "س ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) like a mirage",
        "waznTlit": "sarāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِرَاجًا",
        "answer": "a lamp",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 677,
        "tlit": "sirājan",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا سِرَاجًا وَهَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "س ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ر ج",
        "waznEnglish": "a lamp",
        "waznTlit": "sīn rā jīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْمَعُونَ",
        "answer": "they will hear",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "yasmaʿūna",
        "frequency": "185",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمِعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hear, to listen",
        "waznTlit": "samiʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the heaven",
        "pcklId": "345",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُتِحَتِ السَّمَاءُ فَكَانَتْ أَبْوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "(of) the heavens",
        "pcklId": "346",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَسُيِّرَتِ",
        "answer": "And are moved",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 750,
        "tlit": "wasuyyirati",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسُيِّرَتِ الْجِبَالُ فَكَانَتْ سَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "س ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُيِّرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to move",
        "waznTlit": "suyyirat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شِدَادًا",
        "answer": "strong",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 762,
        "tlit": "shidādan",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنَيْنَا فَوْقَكُمْ سَبْعًا شِدَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ش د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَدِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "and harden",
        "waznTlit": "shadīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَرَابًا",
        "answer": "any drink",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "sharāban",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا بَرْدًا وَلَا شَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and drink",
        "waznTlit": "sharāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "228",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "515",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلَّ شَيْءٍ أَحْصَيْنَاهُ كِتَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَفًّا",
        "answer": "(in) rows",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 849,
        "tlit": "ṣaffan",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَقُومُ الرُّوحُ وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَفّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(when) lined up",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaff",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَوَابًا",
        "answer": "(what is) correct",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 867,
        "tlit": "ṣawāban",
        "frequency": "77",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "14",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ص و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَوَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "strikes them",
        "waznTlit": "ṣawāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصُّورِ",
        "answer": "the trumpet",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 869,
        "tlit": "l-ṣūri",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُنْفَخُ فِي الصُّورِ فَتَأْتُونَ أَفْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ص و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُّور",
        "waznEnglish": "and incline them",
        "waznTlit": "ṣūr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلطَّاغِينَ",
        "answer": "For the transgressors",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "lilṭṭāghīna",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِلطَّاغِينَ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَٰغِين",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāghīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابًا",
        "answer": "(in) punishment",
        "pcklId": "355",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhāban",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذُوقُوا فَلَنْ نَزِيدَكُمْ إِلَّا عَذَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابًا",
        "answer": "(of) a punishment",
        "pcklId": "356",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhāban",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُعْصِرَاتِ",
        "answer": "the rain clouds",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 993,
        "tlit": "l-muʿ'ṣirāti",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ الْمُعْصِرَاتِ مَاءً ثَجَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُعْصِرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "pressing",
        "waznTlit": "muʿ'ṣirāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَطَاءً",
        "answer": "a gift",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1004,
        "tlit": "ʿaṭāan",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً مِنْ رَبِّكَ عَطَاءً حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَطَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "and he took",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Great",
        "pcklId": "110",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmi",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ النَّبَإِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "(soon) they will know",
        "pcklId": "370",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "sayaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا سَيَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "(soon) they will know",
        "pcklId": "371",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "sayaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ كَلَّا سَيَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَعْنَابًا",
        "answer": "and grapevines",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1026,
        "tlit": "wa-aʿnāban",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " حَدَائِقَ وَأَعْنَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ن ب",
        "waznEnglish": "and grapevines",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn nūn bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعَاشًا",
        "answer": "(for) livelihood",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1044,
        "tlit": "maʿāshan",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا النَّهَارَ مَعَاشًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَعَاش",
        "waznEnglish": "a life",
        "waznTlit": "maʿāsh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَغَسَّاقًا",
        "answer": "and purulence",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1062,
        "tlit": "waghassāqan",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا حَمِيمًا وَغَسَّاقًا",
        "rootWord": "غ س ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَسَّاق",
        "waznEnglish": "and purulence",
        "waznTlit": "ghassāq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفُتِحَتِ",
        "answer": "And is opened",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1101,
        "tlit": "wafutiḥati",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُتِحَتِ السَّمَاءُ فَكَانَتْ أَبْوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَتَحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to open, to give victory",
        "waznTlit": "fataḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ كَانَ مِيقَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفْوَاجًا",
        "answer": "(in) crowds",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1160,
        "tlit": "afwājan",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُنْفَخُ فِي الصُّورِ فَتَأْتُونَ أَفْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ف و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف و ج",
        "waznEnglish": "a troop",
        "waznTlit": "fā wāw jīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَفَازًا",
        "answer": "(is) success",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1162,
        "tlit": "mafāzan",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ مَفَازًا",
        "rootWord": "ف و ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَفَاز",
        "waznEnglish": "he is successful",
        "waznTlit": "mafāz",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَوْقَكُمْ",
        "answer": "over you",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1164,
        "tlit": "fawqakum",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَبَنَيْنَا فَوْقَكُمْ سَبْعًا شِدَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ف و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوْق",
        "waznEnglish": "he recovered",
        "waznTlit": "fawq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّمَتْ",
        "answer": "have sent forth",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1183,
        "tlit": "qaddamat",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق د م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send forth, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "qaddama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرِيبًا",
        "answer": "near",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 1187,
        "tlit": "qarīban",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرِيب",
        "waznEnglish": "[you two] approach",
        "waznTlit": "qarīb",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالَ",
        "answer": "and he (will) say",
        "pcklId": "1599",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqāla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "13",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَقُولُ",
        "answer": "and will say",
        "pcklId": "1600",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "wayaqūlu",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُ الْكَافِرُ يَا لَيْتَنِي كُنْتُ تُرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُومُ",
        "answer": "will stand",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "yaqūmu",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَقُومُ الرُّوحُ وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَامَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to stand up, to rise, to establish",
        "waznTlit": "qāma",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَأْسًا",
        "answer": "And a cup",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1250,
        "tlit": "wakasan",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَأْسًا دِهَاقًا",
        "rootWord": "ك أ س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك أ س",
        "waznEnglish": "a cup",
        "waznTlit": "kāf hamza sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِتَابًا",
        "answer": "(in) a Book",
        "pcklId": "300",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "kitāban",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلَّ شَيْءٍ أَحْصَيْنَاهُ كِتَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَذَّبُوا",
        "answer": "And they denied",
        "pcklId": "173",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "wakadhabū",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِذَّابًا",
        "answer": "(with) denial",
        "pcklId": "259",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kidhāban",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبُوا بِآيَاتِنَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِذَّاب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kidhāb",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِذَّابًا",
        "answer": "any falsehood",
        "pcklId": "260",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kidhāban",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِذَّاب",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "kidhāb",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَوَاعِبَ",
        "answer": "And splendid companions",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1277,
        "tlit": "wakawāʿiba",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَوَاعِبَ أَتْرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ع ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَوَاعِب",
        "waznEnglish": "the ankles",
        "waznTlit": "kawāʿib",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَافِرُ",
        "answer": "the disbeliever",
        "pcklId": "327",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "l-kāfiru",
        "frequency": "525",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُ الْكَافِرُ يَا لَيْتَنِي كُنْتُ تُرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَافِر",
        "waznEnglish": "disbelieve[d]",
        "waznTlit": "kāfir",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُلَّ",
        "answer": "And every",
        "pcklId": "352",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "wakulla",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكُلَّ شَيْءٍ أَحْصَيْنَاهُ كِتَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَكَلَّمُونَ",
        "answer": "they will speak",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1289,
        "tlit": "yatakallamūna",
        "frequency": "75",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَتَكَلَّمُونَ إِلَّا مَنْ أَذِنَ لَهُ الرَّحْمَٰنُ وَقَالَ صَوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَكَلَّمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to speak",
        "waznTlit": "yatakallamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "is",
        "pcklId": "1338",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ كَانَ مِيقَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانَتْ",
        "answer": "and becomes",
        "pcklId": "1339",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānat",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفُتِحَتِ السَّمَاءُ فَكَانَتْ أَبْوَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانَتْ",
        "answer": "and become",
        "pcklId": "1340",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānat",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسُيِّرَتِ الْجِبَالُ فَكَانَتْ سَرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَتْ",
        "answer": "is",
        "pcklId": "1341",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānat",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ جَهَنَّمَ كَانَتْ مِرْصَادًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "were",
        "pcklId": "1342",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا لَا يَرْجُونَ حِسَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُ",
        "answer": "I were",
        "pcklId": "1343",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntu",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "14",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُ الْكَافِرُ يَا لَيْتَنِي كُنْتُ تُرَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَابِثِينَ",
        "answer": "(They will) be remaining",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1313,
        "tlit": "lābithīna",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لَابِثِينَ فِيهَا أَحْقَابًا",
        "rootWord": "ل ب ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَّٰبِثِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(have) you remained",
        "waznTlit": "lābithīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِبَاسًا",
        "answer": "(as) covering",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1315,
        "tlit": "libāsan",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا اللَّيْلَ لِبَاسًا",
        "rootWord": "ل ب س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لِبَاس",
        "waznEnglish": "mix",
        "waznTlit": "libās",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَغْوًا",
        "answer": "any vain talk",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1336,
        "tlit": "laghwan",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَسْمَعُونَ فِيهَا لَغْوًا وَلَا كِذَّابًا",
        "rootWord": "ل غ و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَغْو",
        "waznEnglish": "and make noise",
        "waznTlit": "laghū",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْفَافًا",
        "answer": "(of) thick foliage",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1340,
        "tlit": "alfāfan",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَنَّاتٍ أَلْفَافًا",
        "rootWord": "ل ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْفَاف",
        "waznEnglish": "And is wound",
        "waznTlit": "alfāf",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّيْلَ",
        "answer": "the night",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "al-layla",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا اللَّيْلَ لِبَاسًا",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَرْءُ",
        "answer": "the man",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "l-maru",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْء",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "mar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَمْلِكُونَ",
        "answer": "they have power",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "yamlikūna",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا الرَّحْمَٰنِ لَا يَمْلِكُونَ مِنْهُ خِطَابًا",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to possess, to have power",
        "waznTlit": "malakat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ",
        "answer": "and the Angels",
        "pcklId": "146",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "wal-malāikatu",
        "frequency": "206",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَقُومُ الرُّوحُ وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِهَادًا",
        "answer": "a resting place",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1421,
        "tlit": "mihādan",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ مِهَادًا",
        "rootWord": "م ه د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِهَٰد",
        "waznEnglish": "they are preparing",
        "waznTlit": "mihād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَاءً",
        "answer": "water",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "māan",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ الْمُعْصِرَاتِ مَاءً ثَجَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّبَإِ",
        "answer": "the News",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "l-naba-i",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنِ النَّبَإِ الْعَظِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَأ",
        "waznEnglish": "Shall I inform you",
        "waznTlit": "naba",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَبَاتًا",
        "answer": "and vegetation",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1435,
        "tlit": "wanabātan",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لِنُخْرِجَ بِهِ حَبًّا وَنَبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَات",
        "waznEnglish": "(which) produces",
        "waznTlit": "nabāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "[We] have warned you",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "andharnākum",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنذَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to warn",
        "waznTlit": "andhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَنْزَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We sent down",
        "pcklId": "249",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "wa-anzalnā",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ الْمُعْصِرَاتِ مَاءً ثَجَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْظُرُ",
        "answer": "will see",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "yanẓuru",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّظَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look, to see",
        "waznTlit": "naẓara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنْفَخُ",
        "answer": "(in which) shall be blown",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1496,
        "tlit": "yunfakhu",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُنْفَخُ فِي الصُّورِ فَتَأْتُونَ أَفْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ف خ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفَخَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to blow, to breathe",
        "waznTlit": "nafakha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّهَارَ",
        "answer": "the day",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1525,
        "tlit": "l-nahāra",
        "frequency": "113",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا النَّهَارَ مَعَاشًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَار",
        "waznEnglish": "repel them",
        "waznTlit": "nahār",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَوْمَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your sleep",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1534,
        "tlit": "nawmakum",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا نَوْمَكُمْ سُبَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ن و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "your dream",
        "waznTlit": "nawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوْتَادًا",
        "answer": "(as) pegs",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1582,
        "tlit": "awtādan",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجِبَالَ أَوْتَادًا",
        "rootWord": "و ت د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ت د",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the stakes",
        "waznTlit": "wāw tā dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وِفَاقًا",
        "answer": "appropriate",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1632,
        "tlit": "wifāqan",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " جَزَاءً وِفَاقًا",
        "rootWord": "و ف ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وِفَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "will cause reconciliation",
        "waznTlit": "wifāq",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِيقَاتًا",
        "answer": "an appointed time",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1635,
        "tlit": "mīqātan",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ كَانَ مِيقَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "و ق ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِيقَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "are gathered to their appointed time",
        "waznTlit": "mīqāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "for the righteous",
        "pcklId": "257",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "lil'muttaqīna",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ مَفَازًا",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَهَّاجًا",
        "answer": "burning",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1651,
        "tlit": "wahhājan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا سِرَاجًا وَهَّاجًا",
        "rootWord": "و ه ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ه ج",
        "waznEnglish": "burning",
        "waznTlit": "wāw hā jīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَدَاهُ",
        "answer": "his hands",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 1657,
        "tlit": "yadāhu",
        "frequency": "120",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "ي د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي د ي",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) them",
        "waznTlit": "yā dāl yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "315",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ كَانَ مِيقَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "316",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُنْفَخُ فِي الصُّورِ فَتَأْتُونَ أَفْوَاجًا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Day",
        "pcklId": "317",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "l-yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ الْيَوْمُ الْحَقُّ فَمَنْ شَاءَ اتَّخَذَ إِلَىٰ رَبِّهِ مَآبًا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "394",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يَقُومُ الرُّوحُ وَالْمَلَائِكَةُ صَفًّا",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "395",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "78",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْذَرْنَاكُمْ عَذَابًا قَرِيبًا يَوْمَ يَنْظُرُ الْمَرْءُ مَا قَدَّمَتْ يَدَاهُ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    }
]